<diagram1>
Filename: crop_to_cloud_data_flow_part1.png
Name: Crop to Cloud Data Flow - Part 1
Description: Illustrates the journey of data from field sensors to the MQTT broker, showcasing the initial stages of data collection and transmission in the IoT system.
Code:
sequenceDiagram
    participant Sensors as Field Sensors
    participant Logger as Campbell CR800 Logger
    participant RPi as Raspberry Pi
    participant LoRaHAT as LoRa HAT
    participant Gateway as LoRa Gateway
    participant EMQX as EMQX MQTT Broker

    Sensors->>Logger: Send sensor data
    Logger->>RPi: Transfer raw data 
    (every 30 min)
    RPi->>RPi: Process and format data
    RPi->>RPi: Convert to hashes
    RPi->>LoRaHAT: Send formatted data
    LoRaHAT->>Gateway: Transmit data packet
    Gateway->>EMQX: Publish to MQTT topic
    Note over EMQX: Data ready 
    for cloud processing
</diagram1>

<diagram2>
Filename: crop_to_cloud_data_flow_part2.png
Name: Crop to Cloud Data Flow - Part 2
Description: Depicts the cloud-based processing of irrigation data, from MQTT broker to BigQuery storage, including PubSub messaging and Cloud Function computations.
Code:
sequenceDiagram
    participant EMQX as EMQX MQTT Broker
    participant VM as Virtual Machine Forwarder
    participant PubSub as Google Cloud PubSub
    participant CF as Cloud Function
    participant BQ as BigQuery
    participant Scheduler as Cloud Scheduler

    EMQX->>VM: Forward MQTT message
    VM->>VM: Process message
    VM->>PubSub: Publish to PubSub topic
    PubSub->>CF: Trigger Cloud Function
    CF->>CF: Process data
    CF->>BQ: Insert into BigQuery table
    Scheduler->>CF: Trigger periodic functions
    Note over CF: CWSI, ET_ref, 
    SWSI computations
    CF->>BQ: Update computed metrics
</diagram2>

<diagram3>
Filename: cloud_functions_workflow.png
Name: Cloud Functions Workflow
Description: Provides an overview of various cloud functions, including weather data retrieval, forecasting, and irrigation metric computations, showing how these functions interact with BigQuery and are triggered by Cloud Scheduler.
Code:
graph TD
    A[Cloud Scheduler] -->|Triggers| B(Current Weather Function)
    A -->|Triggers| C(Forecast Function)
    A -->|Triggers| D(CWSI Computation)
    A -->|Triggers| E(ET_ref Calculation)
    A -->|Triggers| F(SWSI Computation)
    B -->|Updates| G[BigQuery Tables]
    C -->|Updates| G
    D -->|Updates| G
    E -->|Updates| G
    F -->|Updates| G
    H[PubSub Messages] -->|Trigger| I(Data Insertion Function)
    I -->|Inserts Data| G
</diagram3>

<diagram4>
Filename: complete_sensor_to_cloud_workflow.png
Name: Complete Sensor-to-Cloud Data Flow
Description: The image shows a left-to-right flow diagram of a data collection and processing system. It consists of several components connected by red arrows.

Starting from the left:

1. There are three small images labeled "SENSORS (ORIGIN)":
   - A close-up of a plant stem labeled "STEM DIAMETER"
   - A device pointing upward labeled "CANOPY TEMPERATURE"
   - Yellow cables in soil labeled "SOIL MOISTURE"

2. A red arrow points from these to the next major component:
   - A large image of an open electrical box with various components inside
   - Labels point to different parts:
     - "CAMPBELL DATALOGGER" at the top
     - "LORA ANTENNA" also at the top
     - "RBPI" (likely Raspberry Pi) in the middle
     - "LORA HAT" below the RBPI
     - "CHARGE CONTROLLER" to the right
     - "12V BATTERY" at the bottom
     - "POWER REGULATOR" also at the bottom

3. Another red arrow points to the next item:
   - A white, rectangular device labeled "LORAWAN GATEWAY"

4. The next red arrow points to:
   - A purple logo with white text reading "MQTT Broker"

5. Below this, connected by a red arrow, is:
   - A blue square with an icon of a computer screen, labeled "VM" and "MQTT PACKET FOWARDED" (likely a typo for "FORWARDER")

6. To the right, connected by a red arrow:
   - A blue hexagon with white dots and lines, labeled "GOOGLE PUB/SUB"

7. Next to this, connected by a double-headed arrow:
   - Another blue hexagon with brackets, labeled "GOOGLE CLOUD FUNCTIONS"

8. A final red arrow points to:
   - A screenshot of a spreadsheet-like interface labeled "GOOGLE BIGQUERY (DESTINATION)"

The overall layout suggests a flow of data from sensors on the left, through various processing and transmission stages, to final storage and analysis on the right.
</diagram4>


<diagram5>
Filename: agricultural_iot_dashboard.png
Name: Agricultural IoT Analytics Dashboard
Description: The image shows a web-based dashboard interface designed for agricultural data visualization and analysis. The dashboard is divided into several distinct sections:

1. Header:
   - Top left: A logo showing a stylized leaf and the text "AgriSense IoT"
   - Top right: User profile icon, notifications bell, and settings gear icon

2. Left Sidebar:
   - Navigation menu with icons and labels for: Home, Fields, Sensors, Analytics, Alerts, and Settings

3. Main Content Area (divided into a 2x2 grid of widgets):
   Top Left Widget - "Field Overview":
   - A satellite map view of agricultural fields
   - Fields are color-coded based on soil moisture levels
   - A legend shows colors ranging from red (dry) to blue (wet)

   Top Right Widget - "Sensor Readings":
   - Three gauges showing current readings for:
     1. Average Soil Moisture: 32%
     2. Average Canopy Temperature: 28°C
     3. Average Stem Diameter: 15mm
   - Each gauge has a needle pointing to the current value and is color-coded (green, yellow, or red) to indicate status

   Bottom Left Widget - "7-Day Trend":
   - A line graph showing the last 7 days of data
   - Y-axis: Values for soil moisture, temperature, and stem diameter
   - X-axis: Dates
   - Three lines in different colors represent each measurement type

   Bottom Right Widget - "Alerts and Recommendations":
   - A scrollable list of recent alerts and AI-generated recommendations, such as:
     1. "Field 3 soil moisture below threshold - Consider irrigation"
     2. "Predicted heat stress in Field 2 - Increase monitoring"
     3. "Optimal harvest time for Field 1 approaching - Schedule equipment"

4. Footer:
   - Links to "Help", "Contact Support", and "Privacy Policy"
   - Text showing "Last updated: [Current Date and Time]"

The overall color scheme uses shades of green and blue, evoking an agricultural and technological feel. The layout is clean and modern, with clear data visualizations and actionable insights prominently displayed.
</diagram5>
